samebug.io 2018-10-01

# Privacy Policy

Effective date: May 25, 2018

Thanks for entrusting Samebug with your stack trace, your projects, and your personal information. Holding onto your private information is a serious responsibility, and we want you to know how we're handling it. If you have any concerns, requests or questions, contact us at [privacy@samebug.io](mailto:privacy@samebug.io).

**The short version**

We collect your information only with your consent; we only collect the minimum amount of personal information that is necessary to fulfil the purpose of your interaction with us; we don't sell it to third parties; and we only use it as this Privacy Statement describes.

Of course, the short version doesn't tell you everything, so please read on for more details!

**Table of content**  
  
---  
What information Samebug collects and why  
What information Samebug does not collect  
How we share the information we collect  
How Samebug secures your information  
Resolving Complaints  
How we respond to compelled disclosure  
How you can access and control the information we collect  
How we communicate with you  
Changes to our Privacy Statement  
License  
Contacting Samebug  
  
* * *

### What information Samebug collects and why

**Quick Reference**

IP address:

  * Collected in the webserver (nginx) logs, and in our custom tracking server
  * We use it to 
    * Audience measurement - Identify visitor behaviour and geological location of users
    * Fraud detection - ban users abusing the service
  * To opt out of all tracking go to your [profile](https://samebug.io/profile) settings.

Browser and device info:

  * Collected in our custom tracking server
  * We use it to 
    * Track browser preferences
    * Track screen size
    * Track operating system preferences
  * Used for optimizing features and prioritising fixes

Tracking cookies

  * Complete overview on <https://samebug.io/cookie-policy>

Email address, full name, display name

  * Only collected for registered users, provided upon registration
  * We use it for 
    * Login identification
    * Communication of important service updates
    * Marketing (only with consent)

3rd parties:

  * Google Analytics 
    * Collects site usage statistics
    * Operates without personal data since the last 3 digits of your IP address are cut off
    * We use it for audience measurement and website performance
    * You can opt out of this on all websites through here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>
    * Learn more about Google Analytics security and privacy here: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>
  * HotJar 
    * Records user sessions: clicks, scrolls and mouse movements
    * All personal information is suppressed so we cannot connect you to your recording
    * We have signed a Data Processor Agreement with HotJar which ensures reasonable privacy and security measures
    * If you really want to opt out of this, you can do so here: <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out>
    * Learn more about Hotjar's privacy here: <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy>
  * MailChimp softwares (Mailchimp, Mandrill, Tinyletter) 
    * Provides email marketing services, stores your email address
    * Upon registration you will be prompted to opt into Mailchimp onboarding emails and Tinyletter newsletter services
    * Further emails will only be sent if you decide to opt in
    * If you want to unsubscribe, there's a button at the bottom of our emails
    * Learn more about Mailchimp's privacy here: <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>

**Information from website browsers**

If you're just browsing the website, we collect the same basic information that most websites collect. We use common internet technologies, such as cookies and web server logs. This is what we collect from everyone, whether they have an account or not.

The information we collect about all visitors to our website includes the visitor's browser type, language preference, referring site, additional websites requested, and the date and time of each visitor request. We also collect potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses.

**Why do we collect this?**

We collect this information to better understand how our website visitors use Samebug, and to monitor and protect the security of the website.

**Information from users with accounts**

If you create an account, we require some basic information at the time of account creation. You will create your own username and password, and we will ask you for a valid email address. You also have the option to give us more information if you want to, and this may include "User Personal Information".

"User Personal Information" is any information about one of our users which could, alone or together with other information, personally identify him or her. Information such as a username and password, an email address, a real name, and a photograph are examples of "User Personal Information".

"User Personal Information" does not include aggregated, non-personally identifying information. We may use aggregated, non-personally identifying information to operate, improve, and optimize our website and service.

**Why do we collect this?**

  * We need your User Personal Information to create your account, and to provide the services you request.
  * We use your User Personal Information, specifically your user name, to identify you on Samebug.
  * We use it to fill out your profile and share that profile with other users if you ask us to.
  * We will use your email address to communicate with you, if you've said that's okay, and only for the reasons you've said that's okay. Please see our section on email communication for more information.
  * We limit our use of your User Personal Information to the purposes listed in this Privacy Statement. If we need to use your User Personal Information for other purposes, we will ask your permission first. You can always see what information we have, how we're using it, and what permissions you have given us in your [user profile](https://samebug.io/profile).

**Cookies**

Samebug uses cookies to make interactions with our service easy and meaningful. We use cookies to keep you logged in, remember your preferences, and provide information for the future development of Samebug.

A cookie is a small piece of text that our web server stores on your computer or mobile device, which your browser sends to us when you return to our site. Cookies do not necessarily identify you if you are merely visiting Samebug; however, a cookie may store a unique identifier for each logged in user. The cookies Samebug sets are essential for the operation of the website, or are used for performance or functionality. By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your computer or device. If you disable your browser or device's ability to accept cookies, you will not be able to log in or use Samebug's services.

Full overview of all our cookies can be found here: <https://samebug.io/cookie-policy>.

**Google Analytics**

We use Google Analytics as a third party tracking service, but we don't use it to track you individually or collect your User Personal Information. We use Google Analytics to collect information about how our website performs and how our users, in general, navigate through and use Samebug. This helps us evaluate our users' use of Samebug; compile statistical reports on activity; and improve our content and website performance.

Google Analytics gathers certain simple, non-personally identifying information over time, such as your IP address, browser type, internet service provider, referring and exit pages, timestamp, and similar data about your use of Samebug. We do not link this information to any of your personal information such as your user name.

Samebug will not, nor will we allow any third party to, use the Google Analytics tool to track our users individually; collect any User Personal Information other than IP address; or correlate your IP address with your identity. Google provides further information about its own privacy practices and offers a [browser add-on to opt out of Google Analytics tracking](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Certain pages on our site may set other third party cookies. For example, we may embed content, such as videos, from another site that sets a cookie. While we try to minimize these third party cookies, we can't always control what cookies this third party content sets.

**Hotjar**

We use [Hotjar](http://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our users' needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don't like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users' behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar's privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar's storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar's use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).

* * *

### What information Samebug does not collect

We do not intentionally collect sensitive personal information, such as social security numbers, genetic data, health information, or religious information. Although Samebug does not request or intentionally collect any sensitive personal information, we realize that you might store this kind of information in your account, such as in a workspace. If you store any sensitive personal information on our servers, you are consenting to our storage of that information on our servers, which are in the United States.

We do not intentionally collect information that is stored in your workspaces or other free-form content inputs. The information in your workspaces belongs to you, and you are responsible for it, as well as for making sure that your content complies with our [Terms of Service](https://samebug.io/terms). Samebug employees do not access private workspaces unless required to for security or maintenance, or for support reasons, with the consent of the workspace owner.

If your workspace is public, anyone (including us) may view its contents. If you have included private or sensitive information in your public workspace, such as email addresses, that information may be indexed by search engines or used by third parties. In addition, while we do not generally search for content in your workspaces, we may scan our servers for certain tokens or security signatures.

If you're a child under the age of 13, you may not have an account on Samebug. Samebug does not knowingly collect information from or direct any of our content specifically to children under 13. If we learn or have reason to suspect that you are a user who is under the age of 13, we will unfortunately have to close your account. We don't want to discourage you from learning to code, but those are the rules. Please see our [Terms of Service](https://samebug.io/terms) for information about account termination.

* * *

### How we share the information we collect

We do not share, sell, rent, or trade User Personal Information with third parties for their commercial purposes.

We do not disclose User Personal Information outside Samebug, except in the situations listed in this section or in the section below on Compelled Disclosure.

We do share certain aggregated, non-personally identifying information with others about how our users, collectively, use Samebug, or how our users respond to our other offerings. For example, we may compile statistics on the usage of components across Samebug. However, we do not sell this information to advertisers or marketers.

We do not host advertising on Samebug.

We may share User Personal Information with your permission, so we can perform services you have requested.

We may share User Personal Information with a limited number of third-party vendors who process it on our behalf to provide or improve our service, and who have agreed to privacy restrictions similar to our own Privacy Statement. Our vendors perform services such as payment processing, customer support ticketing, network data transmission, and other similar services.

We may share User Personal Information if we are involved in a merger, sale, or acquisition. If any such change of ownership happens, we will ensure that it is under terms that preserve the confidentiality of User Personal Information, and we will notify you on our website or by email before any transfer of your User Personal Information. The organization receiving any User Personal Information will have to honor any promises we have made in our Privacy Statement or in our [Terms of Service](https://samebug.io/terms).

**Public Information on Samebug**

Much of Samebug is public-facing. If your content is public-facing, third parties may access and use it in compliance with our [Terms of Service](https://samebug.io/terms). We do not sell that content; it is yours. However, we do allow third parties, such as research organizations or archives, to compile public-facing Samebug information.

Your Personal Information, associated with your content, may be gathered by third parties in these compilations of Samebug data. Personal Information you shared on your profile may appear in third parties' compilations of Samebug data. Please note that your email address is always kept private.

If you would like to compile Samebug data, you may only use any public-facing Personal Information you gather for the purpose for which our user has authorized it. For example, where a Samebug user has made an email address public-facing for the purpose of identification and attribution, do not use that email address for commercial advertising. We expect you to reasonably secure any Personal Information you have gathered from Samebug, and to respond promptly to complaints, removal requests, and "do not contact" requests from Samebug or Samebug users.

Similarly, any content on Samebug may include publicly available Personal Information collected as part of the collaborative process. In the event that a Samebug content contains publicly available Personal Information that does not belong to Samebug users, we will only use that Personal Information for the limited purpose for which it was collected, and we will secure that Personal Information as we would secure any User Personal Information. If you have a complaint about any Personal Information on Samebug, please see our section on resolving complaints.

* * *

### How Samebug secures your information

Samebug takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect User Personal Information from unauthorized access, alteration, or destruction; maintain data accuracy; and help ensure the appropriate use of User Personal Information. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.

No method of transmission, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Samebug's global privacy practices**

Information that we collect will be stored and processed in the United States in accordance with this Privacy Statement. However, we understand that we have users from different countries and regions with different privacy expectations, and we try to meet those needs.

* * *

### Resolving Complaints

If you have concerns about the way Samebug is handling your User Personal Information, please let us know immediately. We want to help. You may email us directly at [privacy@samebug.io](mailto:privacy@samebug.io) with the subject line "Privacy Concerns." We will respond within 30 days at the latest.

* * *

### How we respond to compelled disclosure

Samebug may disclose personally-identifying information or other information we collect about you to law enforcement in response to a valid subpoena, court order, warrant, or similar government order, or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect our property or rights, or those of third parties or the public at large.

In complying with court orders and similar legal processes, Samebug strives for transparency. When permitted, we will make a reasonable effort to notify users of any disclosure of their information, unless we are prohibited by law or court order from doing so, or in rare, exigent circumstances.

* * *

### How you can access and control the information we collect

If you're already a Samebug user, you may access, update, alter, or delete your basic user profile information by [editing your settings](https://samebug.io/profile) or contacting Samebug support at [privacy@samebug.io](mailto:privacy@samebug.io).

You can have a full overview of your rights regarding the information we collected on you here: <https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/>

**Data Retention and Deletion**

Samebug will retain User Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.

We may retain certain User Personal Information indefinitely, unless you delete it or request its deletion. For example, we don't automatically delete inactive user accounts, so unless you choose to delete your account, we will retain your account information indefinitely.

If you would like to cancel your account or delete your User Personal Information, you may do so by sending an email to [privacy@samebug.io](mailto:privacy@samebug.io). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements, but barring legal requirements, we will delete your full profile (within reason) within 30 days.

* * *

### How we communicate with you

We will use your email address to communicate with you. Samebug may occasionally send notification emails about new content related to your stack traces, new features, requests for feedback, important policy changes, or to offer customer support. We also send marketing emails, but only with your consent. There's an unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each of the emails we send you.

* * *

### Changes to our Privacy Statement

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Samebug may change our Privacy Statement from time to time. We will provide notification to Users of material changes to this Privacy Statement through our Website at least 30 days prior to the change taking effect by posting a notice on our homepage or sending email to the email address specified in your Samebug primary account. For changes to this Privacy Statement that do not affect your rights, we encourage visitors to check this page frequently.

* * *

### License

This Privacy Statement is licensed under this [Creative Commons Zero license](https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/).

* * *

### Contacting Samebug

Questions regarding Samebug's Privacy Statement or information practices should be directed to our [privacy@samebug.io](mailto:privacy@samebug.io).
